# Matheus Torquato

Computer Engineer, MSc.

#### Contact

## Summary

Swansea, Wales United Kingdom

Matheusft@gmail.com

## **Expertise**

Artificial Intelligence,
Machine Learning,
Data Science, Data
Mining, Embedded
Computing, Digital
Systems,
Reconfigurable
Computing and
Human-Computer
Interaction.

### Skills

Python, MATLAB,
TensorFlow, Scikit
Learn, Pandas,
NumPy, SciPy, Version
control systems,
Translating complex
scientific concepts to
non-experts,
Proactivity,
Organisation,
Communication,
Responsibility and
Discipline

#### Certification

Huawei Certified ICT Associate – Artificial Intelligence

## Languages

English Portuguese

BEng and MSc in Computer Engineering. Three years of experience in applying Machine Learning to manufacturing processes. Expertise in scientific and applied research in the topics of Artificial Intelligence, Data Science, Embedded Computing, Digital Systems and Human-Computer Interaction. Well-developed skills employing scientific methods through experimental design, exploratory data analysis and hypothesis testing. Enthusiastic about utilising novel analytical approaches to address real-world challenges and improve commercial outcomes with data. Looking to learn on a daily basis, knowledge is never too much.

## **Experience**

#### 2018-Now **ASTUTE 2020**

Project Assistant (Machine Learning) - June to Now

• Leading the development of projects involving machine learning, data science, computer vision and optimisation.

- Designing regression, classification and predictive models for different processes in the Welsh manufacturing sector.
- Delivering actionable insights from industrial datasets focusing on supporting managerial informed decisions.

#### 2015-2015 Tata Steel

Port Talbot, Wales, UK

Swansea, Wales, UK

Process Control Engineering Trainee - September to October

- Developed a mobile app (VB programming language) for logging field measurements, previously performed manually.
- Collaborated in the selection of power metering devices for updating the company's high voltage substation network.

#### 2014-2014 **Petrobras**

Natal, RN, Brazil

Natal, RN, Brazil

Engineering Intern - March to May

 Assisted in the final stage of a Programmable Logic Controller ladder code development.

#### 2014–2014 National Institute for Space Research (INPE)

Engineering Intern - January to March

 Coded a frequency-based signal detecting software (MATLAB) used by low altitude satellites.

## **Education**

2016-2017	Masters in Computer Engineering  Final Mark: 10/10   Included A Period in The SMART Lab (Ottawa, Canada)  As A Visiting Researcher.
2014-2015	<b>Undergraduate</b> in Computer Science Swansea University - Swansea, Wales Final Mark: 7.1/10   Scholarship Awarded from The Science Without Borders Programme
2013–2015	<b>Undergraduate</b> in Computer Engineering UFRN - Brazil Final Mark: 9.6/10   Result Among the Top 0.16% Highest in The History of This Undergraduate Course.

## **Additional Activities**

2020	Project Development Github  Modelling ML
2020	Online Course Quantitative Finance & Algorithmic Trading in Python
2019	Online Course Python for Financial Analysis and Algorithmic Trading
2018	Online Course University of Michigan - edX Introduction to User Experience
2015	<b>Volunteer Researcher</b> Future Interaction Technology Lab - Swansea University Volunteer Researcher in the field of Human-Computer Interaction.
2014	<b>Research Project</b> Machine Learning and Intelligent Instrumentation Laboratory - UFRN Embedded Applications Using Microcontrollers and FPGA.
2013	Research Project Computer Engineering Department - UFRN Using Computational Tools in Wind Turbine Study.

## **Publications**

2021	<b>Journal Paper</b> Nature Communications Evaluating the burden of COVID-19 on hospital resources in Bahia, Brazil: A modelling-based analysis of 14.8 million individuals.
2019	<b>Journal Paper</b> Circuits, Systems, and Signal Processing High-Performance Parallel Implementation of Genetic Algorithm on FPGA.
2019	<b>Journal Paper</b> Parallel Implementation of Reinforcement Learning Q-Learning Technique for FPGA.
2019	<b>Journal Paper</b> Deep Neural Network Hardware Implementation Based on Stacked Sparse Autoencoder.
2016	<b>Journal Paper - (Honorable Mention)</b> CHI 2016 Emergeables: Deformable Displays for Continuous Eyes-Free Mobile Interaction.